Usama Saddiq

Melbourne, Victoria, Australia



usama.saddiq11@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/usamasaddiq

Summary

I'm a polyglot developer with over 7 years of professional experience.

I'm experienced in Ruby on Rails, React, AWS and Typescript plus professional exposure to Python. Golang, Docker and Vue. I have extensive experience building resilient systems serving hundreds of thousands of users and I'm extremely passionate about to BDD.

Experience



Senior Software Engineer

SEEK

Feb 2023 - Present (5 months)

Software Engineer

Immutable

Sep 2022 - Dec 2022 (4 months)

B. Co-Founder

Bree.

May 2022 - Dec 2022 (8 months)

Senior Developer

Emmi

Jun 2022 - Aug 2022 (3 months)

Software Engineer

Envato

May 2019 - Jun 2022 (3 years 2 months)

Full Stack Developer

InfoCentric

Feb 2018 - May 2019 (1 year 4 months)

C Full Stack Developer

Curio

Dec 2017 - Dec 2017 (1 month)



RoomRanger

Aug 2017 - Nov 2017 (4 months)

Education



Swinburne University of Technology

Bachelor of Computer Science, Software Development 2016 - 2018

Skills

Software Development • Back-End Web Development • Docker • TypeScript • React Native • React.js • Ruby on Rails • Amazon Web Services (AWS)